Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: [C] Correspondence, (8 Boxes: Boxes 7-14)
  - Smith, Winthrop H.
    - 1947 Oct 28; t.l.s. 1 p; luncheon plans - study of "Effects of Taxation on Business"; NB, Harvard School of Business, Merrill Foundation (Box 13)
  - Smyth, Bruno
    - 1937 Apr 3; a.l.s. 1 p; to editors of The Nation; praises "Adam Smith is Pleased" (Box 13)
    - 1937 Apr 8; carbon 1 p; reply to 4/3 (Box 13)
  - Snyder, Carl
    - 1921 Sep 27; t.l.s. 2 p; Cassel and exchange stabilization; purchasing power parity history - Goshen, Ricardo, Keynes, Bonn, Schumpeter, Davenport, Hollander (Box 13)
    - 1934 Feb 23; t.l.s. 2 p; WCM article for Spiethoff volume, on current depression; own York (Box 13)
    - 1934 Feb 24; carbon 2 p; WCU reply to 2/23; existence of cycles and general index; approach differences (Box 13)
  - Sombart, Werner
    - 1910 Aug lo; a.l.s. 2 p; (on Sombart's card); J.B. Clark, Fisher, Seligman, Veblen; WCM "Rationality of Economic Activity" (Box 13)
    - 1937 Jan 14; copy 1 p; to Eco Press; Plotnike book on Sombart; K. Geiser; Spiethoff (Box 13)
  - Spule, George
    - 1924 Dec 4; t.l.s. 1 p; New Republic and Labor Bureau - wants approval by WCM, Wolman, and Stewart of Bureau program; sends memorandum (not encl.) (Box 13)
    - 1937 Feb 10; t.l.s. 1 p; requests article for New Republic on forestalling depression; own article on NB (Box 13)
    - 1937 Feb 12; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/10; refusal; NB and Willits (Box 13)
    - 1937 Nov 29; t.l.s. 2 p; requests suggestions on proposed National Economic and Social Planning Association study of government cycle policy - Riefler, Mills, J. M. Clark, Dewhurst, A. Wasserman, Berridge, Knauth (Box 13)
    - 1937 Dec 10; t.l.s. 1 p; sends questionnaire on policy opinions (not encl.) (Box 13)
    - 1937 Dec 15; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/10 refuses answer questionnaire (Box 13)
  - Souter, Malvena
    - 1946 Oct 9; a.l.s. 2 p; reply; thanks for condolences on R. Souter’s death; obituary clipping encl. (Box 13)
  - Spahr, Walter E.
    - 1935 Apr 5; carbon 1 p; criticizes manifesto of Economists' National Committee on Monetary Policy.; resigns (Box 13)
    - 1935 Apr 9; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/5 (Box 13)
  - Sprague, Everett T.
    - 1938 Sep 7; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy "Dynamics of Enterprise" (encl. 12 P) (Box 13)
    - 1938 [n.d.]; t.l.s. 4 p; cycles as "beats", rate of business growth (Box 13)
  - Sprang, Kenneth M.
    - 1939 Apr 22; t.l.s. 1 p; wants to study interest rate cycles for NB (Box 13)
  - Sproul, Allan
    - 1947 May 23; t.l.s. 1 p; luncheon plans, D. McLaughlin (Box 13)
    - 1947 Oct 34; a.l.s. 3 p; reply to 10/5; WCM health luncheons (Box 13)
  - Sproul, Robert G.
    - 1)
      - 1933 Jan 10; t.l.s. 1 p; invitation to be Hitchcock lecturer at University of California (Box 13)
      - 1933 Jan 25; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 1/1° (Box 13)
      - 1933 Feb 8; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 1/25; California lecture plans (Box 13)
      - 1933 Feb 14; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/8; California lectures and publications (Box 13)
      - 1933 Feb 8; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to l/25 California lecture piano and publication (Box 13)
    - 2)
      - 1934 May 2; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; California lecture (Box 13)
      - 1934 May 14; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/2 (Box 13)
      - 1934 May 19; carbon 1 p; WC2A reply to 5/14; California lectures, outline of topics (Box 13)
      - 1936 Jan 3; t.l.s. 1 p; invitation to receive degree from California (Box 13)
      - 1936 Jan 20; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 1/3; accepts (Box 13)
  - Spurr, William A.
    - 1936 Sep 20; t.l.s. 1 p; on WCM Harvard degree; own work on Japanese business cycles (Box 13)
    - 1936 Sep 25; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 9/20 (Box 13)
    - [1946 or 1947?]; a.l.s. 2 p; thanks for recommendation of self to J. Jackson (Stanford University) (Box 13)
  - Stamp, Lord
    - 1941 Mar [?]; a.l.s. .-2 p; praises WCM - W. Wilkie; English and American economists - Taussig, Bonar, Seligman, Scott and others (Box 13)
  - Stevens, F.C.
    - 1934 Jun 19; t.l.s. 1 p; University of California Hitchock lecture plans (Box 13)
    - 1934 Oct 2; t.l.s. 1 p; California lectures (Box 13)
    - 1934 Oct 6; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/2 (Box 13)
  - Stewart, Walter
    - 1927 Mar 31; see H. Davenport (Box 13)
  - Stocking, George W.
    - 1937 Apr 16; t.l.s. 1 p; needs instruction at University of Texas (Box 13)
    - 1937 Apr 23; carbon 3 p; WCM reply to 4/16; recommends Gaffey, C. Wright, Strayer (Box 13)
    - 1937 Apr 27; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/23; thanks; praises "Adam Smith is Pleased" (Box 13)
  - Stone, N.I.
    - 1936 Sep 21; t.l.s. 1 p; on WCM Harvard degree (Box 13)
    - 1936 Sep 24; carbon 1 p; reply to 9/21 (Box 13)
  - Strong, Benjamin
    - 1921 Oct 24; t.l.s. 1 p; sends report of hearings on Federal Reserve System (not encl.) (Box 13)
    - 1921 Oct 26; carbon 1 p; (on back 10/24); WCM reply to 10/24 (Box 13)
    - 1924 Mar 7; t.l.s. 1 p; invites WCM to private meeting on gold; attached: WCM memorandum on meeting (Box 13)
    - 1927 Mar 21; t.l.s. 3 p; on price decline; wartime income redistribution; asks WCM opinions (Box 13)
    - 1927 Mar 31; carbon 3 p; WCM reply to 3/21 (Box 13)
  - Stuart, Henry W.
    - 1910 Feb 17; a.l.s. 2 p; Crossroad Club plans (Box 13)
    - 1910 Feb 26; a.l.s. 2 p; Crossroad Club plans - Young on Veblen and WCM on the money economy; own Logic of Conduct (Box 13)
    - 1910 Jun 18; a.l.s. 2 p; on article by Judd; Macdougall and Veblen criticism; W. Gregory (Box 13)
  - Sumner, H.B.
    - 1937 Apr 29; a.l.s. 2 p thanks for copy BASM (Balliol College library) query on Sombart translations (Box 13)
    - 1937 May 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/29 (Box 13)
  - Suranyi-Unger, Theo
    - 1937 Jul 4; t.l.s. 1 p; own work and plans (Box 13)
    - 1946 Dec 27; t.l.s. 1 p; own work and plans (Box 13)
  - Tagliacarne, Guglielmo
    - 1947 Jul 21; copy 1 p; to W. Carson; on Edizioni Scientifiche Italian (Box 13)
  - Taussig, FrankW.
    - 1)
      - 1909 Aug 13; a.l.s. 2 p; on Harvard appointment offer (Box 13)
      - 1910 Feb 26; a.l.s. 2 ?; reply; on Harvard offer (Box 13)
      - 1910 Apr 8 [?]; a.l.s. 4 p; on WCM "Rationality of Economic Activity"; Quarterly Journal of Economics rejection of Veblen article (Box 13)
      - 1910 Sep 7; a.l.s. 2 p; J. Norton and Dun price index (Box 13)
      - 1910 Nov 16; t.l.s. 2 p. reply to 11/8; planned WCM review for Quarterly Journal of Economics; cycle statistics; Veblen aid, workmanship article plans (Box 13)
      - 1911 Jan 12; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM review of monetary publications; Bureau of Labor index number; AF.A Review (Box 13)
    - 2)
      - 1911 May 4; t.l.s. 1 p; Moore Note; WCM Monetary Commission paper review (Box 13)
      - [1913 ?], Aug 25; a.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM send manuscript (Box 13)
      - 1913 Oct 18; t.l.s. 8 p; on BC; wants WCM for Harvard lectures (Box 13)
      - 1913 0c£ 23; a.l.s. 2 p; on BC (Box 13)
      - 1913 Nov 4; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM Harvard lecture plans (Box 13)
      - 1913 Nov 8; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM lecture on business cycles (Box 13)
    - 3)
      - 1914 Apr 7; t.l.s. 2 p; G. Wallas book -WCM review; requests review Veblen’s Instinct of Workmanship and Sombart’s Der Bourgeois (Box 13)
      - 1914 Jul 15; a.l.s. 1 p; Veblen and Sombart reviews (Box 13)
      - 1914 Aug 6; a.l.s. 1 p; WCM article (Box 13)
      - 1914 Sep 11; a.l.s. 2 p; Veblen and Sombart reviews - criticism of Veblen; Walling (Box 13)
      - 1915 May 26; t.l.s. 1 p; asks aid for friend, Mr. Putnam; Cross-Piexotto (Box 13)
      - 1923 Feb 16; t.l.s. 1 p; own and Persons’ views on L. Frank note (Box 13)
      - 1923 Feb 28; carbon 1 p; (on back 2/16); WCM reply to 2/16 (Box 13)
    - 4)
      - 1924 Dec 11; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; on Kondratieff and his article (Box 13)
      - 1924 Dec 13; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 12/11 on Kondratieff; Gay (Box 13)
      - 1924 Dec 15; carbon 1 p; WCM reply; refuses seminar lecture invitation; wants Taussig as AEA committee chairman; Kondratieff (Box 13)
      - 1934 Sep 24; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM review of Robbins' Great Depression (Box 13)
      - 1934 Oct: 1; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 9/24; accepts (Box 13)
      - 1934 Oct 4; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 10/1 (Box 13)
    - 5)
      - 1935 Feb 23; t.l.s. 1 p; on Robbins review (Box 13)
      - 1935 Feb 26; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/23; Robbins review and Cornell lecture (Box 13)
      - 1935 Feb 28; t.l.s. 1 p; Robbins review (Box 13)
      - 1935 Mar 6; carbon 1 p; (on back 2/26); WCM reply to 2/28 (Box 13)
      - 1935 Apr 5; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends Robbins review (Box 13)
      - 1935 Apr 8; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/5 (Box 13)
      - 1935 May 9; t.l.s. 1 p; sends Robbins review payment (Box 13)
    - 6)
      - 1936 Apr 24; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Redlich and study of American businessmen, Schumpeter (Box 13)
      - 1936 Apr 28; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/24; Redlich; own book on American business leaders (Box 13)
      - 1936 May 6; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/28 (Box 13)
      - 1936 May 9; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/6; Redlich plans; own book (Box 13)
      - 1936 Dec 28; copy 1 p; thanks for telegram from Columbia Economics Department (Box 13)
      - 1936 Dec 31; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/28 (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Amos E.
    - 1947 Nov 28; t.l.s. 1 p; requests suggestions for head of American University Economics Department (Box 13)
    - 1947 Dec 24; a.l.s. 1 p; requests endorsement W. Brown for Cosmos Club (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Henry C.
    - 1923 Apr 7; t.l.s. 1 p; on President's agricultural conference, overproduction; sends program (encl. 1 p) (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Horace
    - 1936 Oct 15; t.l.s. 1 p; wants to use WCM "Intelligence and the Guidance of Economic Evolution" in economic planning textbook (Box 13)
    - 1936 Oct 21; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/15 gives permission (Box 13)
    - 1936 Jan 22; t.l.s. 1 p; on Social Unit Institute, sends directors list (encl. 1 p) funds request (with W.Morgan) (Box 13)
  - Thorndike, Edward L.
    - 1934 Dec 13; a.l.s. 1 p; birthday dinner message (AAAS) (Box 13)
  - Thorne, Clifford
    - 1910 Nov 3; t.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM as Interstate Commerce Commission witness on railroad rates, requests data (Box 13)
  - Thornton, Richard H.
    - 1935 Feb 13; t.l.s. 1 p; wants to publish WCM Cornell lectures (Henry Holt & Co.) (Box 13)
    - 1935 Feb 16; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/13 (Box 13)
  - Tinbergen, Jan
    - 1938 Jun 28; a.l.s. 2 p; sends own reports for comment (not encl.) (Box 13)
    - 1938 Jul 8; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 6/28; acknowledgement (Box 13)
    - 1938 Nov 1; carbon 3 p; WCM letter; on Tinbergen reports, correlation analysis and cycles, annual data (Box 13)
    - 1938 Dec 11; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 11/l; own studies of series correlation, annual data (Box 13)
  - Tinkhan, George Holden
    - 1947 May 19; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/13; on own forecast of world events in 1943 (encl. 2 p) (Box 13)
  - Titus, Elizabeth L.
    - 1947 Jul 11; t.l.s. 1 p; queries on B. Hoselitz's proposed translation of Menger's Grundsätze der Volkswirtschaftslehre (University of Chicago Press) (Box 13)
    - 1947 Jul 28; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; thanks for aid on Menger (Box 13)
  - Torrey, Clare M.
    - 1934 Dec 17; telegram; birthday dinner message (Box 13)
    - 1947 Jul 15; California group luncheon plans (Box 13)
  - Tugwell, Rexford Guy
    - 1923 Jan 5; t.l.s. 3 p; on WCM papers; Patten’s Theory of Prosperity and economics, human nature and economic change, institutional economics - Clark, M. Hamilton; requests WCM paper for Trend of Economics, lists possible contributors University of California (Box 13)
    - 1934 Dec 16; telegram; birthday dinner message from Economics Department (Box 13)
  - Van Hook, LaRue
    - 1937 Oct 21; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; golf dinner plans (Box 13)
  - Van Kleek, Mary
    - 1925 Nov 6; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM participate in ASA meeting on statistics of labor turnover (Box 13)
    - 1925 Nov 10; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/6; declines (Box 13)
  - Van Sickle, John V.
    - 1935 Mar 23; t.l.s. 2 p; wants WCM at Geneva conference on economic change advising Rockefeller Foundation; Loveday wants WCM at conference on Habeler cycles research; Vienna cycles conference -Morganstern (Box 13)
    - 1935 May 6; t.l.s. 2 p; sends draft agenda (encl. 7 p) - O. Anderson; lists possible conference attendees (Box 13)
    - 1935 Jun 2; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 5/6; on conference, sends memorandum on draft agenda (copy encl. 2 p), O, Anderson; WCM note on sailing dates attached (Box 13)
  - Veblen, Oswald (Box 14)
    - 1926 Jan 6; carbon 1 p; WCU letter; endorses J. Dorfman for research on T. Veblen (Box 14)
  - Veblen, Thorstein
    - 1)
      - 1908 Aug 27; see J. Laughlin (Box 14)
      - 1908 Sep 6; a.l.s. 1 p; sends Laughlin letter (8/27) and tells of own reply (Box 14)
      - 1909 Sep 9; a.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1909 Sep 30; a.l.s. 1 p; plans for "Christian paper" (Box 14)
    - 2)
      - 1909 Nov 3; a.l.s. 1 p; trustees' action; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1909 Dec 1; a.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1910 May 17; a.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1910 Aug 3; a.l.s. 1 p; work difficulties (Box 14)
      - Vernon, Raymond (Box 14)
      - 1946 Nov 15; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy "Report of the Mission on Japanese Combines" (not encl.) (Box 14)
  - Viner, Jacob
    - 1938 Sep 29; t.l.s. 1 p; on WCM letter to A.B. Wolfe (9/18) (Box 14)
  - Walker, Francis
    - 1924 Sep 3; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy Federal Trade Commission Report "Taxation and Tax Exempt Income" (not encl.) (Box 14)
  - Wallace, Henry C.
    - 1922 Jan 12; t.l.s. 2 p; Presidents Agricultural Conference plans (Box 14)
    - 1922 Feb 9; t.l.s. 1 p; copy 1 p; thanks for National Agricultural Conference series (Box 14)
    - 1923 May 1; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for serving on Committee on Agricultural Outlook (Box 14)
    - 1923 Dec 19; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for services (Box 14)
  - Wallas, Graham
    - 1915 Jan 4; a.l.s. 13 p; thanks for copy "Human Behavior and Economics"; London University news; own work and thought; Macdougall and instincts (Box 14)
    - 1915 Feb 3; carbon 3 p; WCM reply to 1/4; social sciences and scientists at Columbia Giddings, Thorndike; reform and study of history of thought; War and U.S.; current depression; Eugenics and Christianity (Box 14)
  - Warburg, Paul M.
    - 1923 Mar 19; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Warburg’s speech to American Acceptance Council; bankers and interest rate variation (Box 14)
    - 1923 Mar 20; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 3/19 (Box 14)
  - Warner, Ethel
    - 1938 Sep 24; t.l.s. 1 p; sends J.M. Clark letter 8/9) (Academy of Political Science) (Box 14)
  - Warshaw, H.T.
    - 1923 Jun 20; t.l.s. 3 p; National Lead Co. and Normal Stock Method of Valuation of Inventory, control of cycle (Box 14)
  - Wasson, R. Gordon
    - 1948 Sep 2; see W.R. Burgess (Box 14)
  - Watkins, Ralph J.
    - 1937 Dec 20; t.l.s. 1 p; sends statement on proposed regional study of cycles (encl. 14 p), J. Van Sickle (Box 14)
  - Weinberger, Otto
    - 1948 Oct 10; carbon 1 p; LSM reply to 8/17; on Weinberger's request for WCM "Prospects of Economics" (Box 14)
  - Weiss, William J.
    - 1947 Sep 5; t.l.s. 1 p; wants meet WCM, study plans, Coolidge (Box 14)
    - 1947 Oct 2; a.l.s. 1 p; study plans and news (Box 14)
    - 1947 Dec 21; t.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 14)
  - Weld, L.D.H.
    - 1922 Feb 6; t.l.s. 1 p; query on 1915-21 price movements and TTCL4 theory; price chart encl. (1 p) (Box 14)
  - Westerfield, Ray Bert
    - 1935 Jul 25; t.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM write textbook on economic principles (Box 14)
  - Weyl, Walker E.
    - 1913 Nov 24; a.l.s. 3 p; praises GPW; on depression earnings statistics (Box 14)
  - White, John R.
    - 1948 Aug 4; t.l.s. 1 p; J. Herbert and integration of knowledge plan; sends Folder (encl.),introductory letter (encl. 1 p) (Laboratory for the Integration of National Knowledge) (Box 14)
  - Wickett, A.
    - 1948 Jul 13; t.l.s. 2 p; requests money for Hoover Birthday Project (Box 14)
    - 1948 Aug 7; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for contribution (Box 14)
  - Wieser, Friedrich von
    - 1)
      - 1923 Dec 12; carbon 1 p; sends copy review Theorie der gesellschaftlichen Wirtschaft and own "Bentham's Felicific Calculus" (Box 14)
      - 1924 Jan 21; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 12/12/23 (Box 14)
      - 1924 Apr 21; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; on translation of Wieser’s Social Economics - Seligman, Hayek; WCM introduction (Box 14)
      - 1924 Jun 11; see E. Seligman (Box 14)
      - 1924 Jun 23; t.l.s. 1 p (Box 14)
      - 1924 Sep 19; a.l.s. 2 p (Box 14)
      - 1924 Sep 23; a.l.s. 2 p (Box 14)
    - 2)
      - 1924 Oct 20; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; translations progress; asks Wieser attend AEA meeting (Box 14)
      - 1924 Dec 9; t.l.s 2 p (Box 14)
      - 1924 Dec 22; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; translation progress; Voergelein (Box 14)
      - 1926 Mar 25; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; thanks for book copy; translation progress, Seligman, Morganstern, Hinrichs (Box 14)
      - 1926 Apr 13; t.l.s. 1 p (Box 14)
      - 1926 May 4; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; translation progress, Wilding, Clinton F. (Box 14)
      - 1943 Nov 15; t.l.s. 2 p; on own book plans - radio broadcasting; sends copy chapter 6 on the "Universal Audience" (encl. 34 p) (Box 14)
  - Wilcox, Walter F.
    - 1)
      - 1915 Jan 14; t.l.s. 1 p; Rubinow's wage statistics article; R. Meeker (Box 14)
      - 1919 Dec 17; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM bibliographical suggestion; sends draft on John Marshall, "A Statistical Hoax" (encl. 2 p) (Box 14)
      - 1924 Oct 10; t.l.s. 1 p; notification of ISI election of WCM, Persons, Hill; sends paper and memorandum (not encl.); Jensen Committee; Neill and bright (Box 14)
      - 1924 Oct 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/10 ISI election; Jensen Committee - sampling (Box 14)
    - 2)
      - 1947 Jun 14; t.l.s. 1 p; apportionment article - Huntington, Chafee; sends - draft on report of Advisory Committee to Director of Census (encl. Z p); copy own article (encl. Z p), copy correspondence with Raymond Pearl (1935) (encl. l p) (Box 14)
      - 1947 Get 8; t.l.s. 1 p; ISI plans; wants WCM start Mills nomination; Kuznets, Reed, Lotka, Marschak (Box 14)
      - 1947 Oct 13; t.l.s. 1 p; t.l.s. Kuznets ISI nomination; Coats, Bowley, Tinbergen; lists American members (Box 14)
      - 1947 Dec 6; a.l.s. 1 p; ISI nominations - Ogburn, Thurstone; appointment - E. Wilson, W. Feller (Box 14)
    - 3)
      - 1949 Jan 23; carbon 1 p; to ?. Notestein; on WCM letter (1/18) on Kuczynski, requests Notestein do Kuczynski obituary; early life details, North (Box 14)
      - 1948 Jan 23; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy letter to Notestein (1/23); apportionment - E. Huntington, Wilson, Feller (Box 14)
      - 1948 Feb 6; carbon 1 p; to E. Huntington; on appointment, query (Box 14)
      - 1948 Jun 26; t.l.s. 1 p; ISI membership policies - Tinbergen letter; women candidates - Cox (Box 14)
      - 1948 Jun 29; see S. Rice (Box 14)
  - Williams, John
    - 1947 Mar 20; t.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 14)
    - 1948 Jan 15; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy own paper on Keynesian economics (ant encl.); Walker medal award (Box 14)
  - Williams, Pierce
    - 1936 Jun 9; t.l.s. 3 p; requests suggestions for researchers in proposed WPA regional study of economic insecurity (Box 14)
    - 1936 Jun 29; t.l.s. 1 p; WPA regional study plans, W. Pabst (Box 14)
    - Williams, Roger J. (Box 14)
    - 1948 Jan 2; t.l.s. 2 p; AAAS symposium plans -"Science of Man"; asks WCM suggestions (Box 14)
  - Willis, H. Parker
    - 1934 Mar 8; t.l.s. 2 p; on 11C?A Laughlin obituary and own dispute with Laughlin over Federal Reserve origins; sends copy own review Laughlin's Federal Reserve Act (encl.) (Box 14)
    - 1937 May 24; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; personal news and comments (Box 14)
    - 1937 Jun 10; t.l.s. 1 p; personal news and comments (Box 14)
  - Willits, Joseph
    - 1)
      - 1939 May 3; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; on R. Lynd's Knowledge for What and own Columbia Economics Club address (Box 14)
      - [1941 Nov ?]; a.l.s. 1 p; sends A. Berle manuscript for comment (Box 14)
      - 1941 Nov 21; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 11/?; value judgments and scientific study - Berle manuscript [copy 2 p] (Box 14)
      - 1941 Dec 29; carbon 5 p; WCM letter on government economic research (Box 14)
    - 2)
      - 1942 May 22; carbon 3 p; WCM letter; on Bonbright letter - social scientists and social policy (Box 14)
      - 1946 Sep 17; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCM address University of Pennsylvania Industrial Research department (Box 14)
      - [1947 Jan ?]; a.l.s. 2 p; on WCM "Role of Research in Economic Progress" (Box 14)
      - 1947 May 11; see W. Phillips (Box 14)
      - 1947 Aug 15; copy 1 p; introduces Ho (Box 14)
  - Wilson, Edwin B.
    - 1)
      - 1934 Oct 5; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; thanks for information on Sapir - Boas retirement; Sauer, Alsbarg, Pacific Regional Committee (SSRC) (Box 14)
      - 1934 Oct 8; t.l.s. 3 p; SSRC and Pacific Coast Conference; Crane, WCM, Alsberg, Munro, J. Miller, Sauer, conference work (Box 14)
      - 1934 Oct 12; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/8; Pacific Coast Conference; meeting plans; NRB report - Delano, Merriam (Box 14)
      - [1934] Dec 1; a.l.s. 2 p; Snyder; Crane and Delano letter - Ogburn and Ruml, WCM, Merriam (Box 14)
      - 1934 Dec 6; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/1; SSRC funds request Bowman, Compton, Science Advisory Council; study plans, H.N. Moore, Delano letter (Box 14)
      - 1934 Dec 7; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 12/6; SSRC work plans, Gay (Box 14)
    - 2)
      - 1935 Feb 27; t.l.s. 2 p; NB and National Academy of Sciences Campbell, Merriam, Lillie; on Federal aid and research; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1935 Feb 28; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/27; on government and research - NRB, SSRC, American Council on Education; meeting plans (Box 14)
      - 1935 May 8; t.l.s. 1 p; on WCM review of L. Robbins' Great Depression (Box 14)
      - 1935 May 10; carbon 1 p; WCM Reply to 5/8; Robbins review; Wilson's "What is a Proof?"; Quarterly Journal of Economics - Taussig and Wilson (Box 14)
    - 3)
      - 1936 Mar 27; t.l.s. 3 p; own work, Burbank, R. Bennett; mathematical economics at Harvard - Schumpeter, Taussig, remedy plans, teaching and use of mathematics; WCM and NB; self and NRC, Committee on the Tercentenary (Gay); SSRC meeting, committee - Shapley, Henderson, Nock, Greene (Box 14)
      - 1933 Mar 31; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 3/27; mathematics, R. Bennett; SSRC meeting, Crane, Committee on Social Security (Box 14)
      - 1936 Apr 50; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Persons, sends W. King materials for Committee to approve the Statistical Evidence of the Causes of the 1929-32 Business Collapse; own criticisms (Box 14)
      - 1936 way 1; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 4/30; King material; science and mathematics; SSRC meeting, Crane, Greene (Box 14)
    - 4)
      - 1938 Dec 11; t.l.s. 2 p; thanks for NB Bulletin no.69; taxonomy and social sciences (Box 14)
      - 1939 Feb 25; t.l.s. 2 p; index numbers and weighting (Box 14)
      - 1939 Oct 30; t.l.s. 1 p; on manuscript of WCM "Public Relations of Science" (Box 14)
      - 1939 Nov 9; t.l.s. 7 p; limitations of social science integration; University of Chicago Centennial celebration (Box 14)
      - 1959 Nov 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/9 (Box 14)
    - 5)
      - 1939 Nov 16; t.l.s. 2 p; SSRC plans - Crane, Redfield, Chicago meeting; on integration policies (Box 14)
      - 1939 Nov 27; carbon 1 p; copy 1 p; WCU reply to 11/15 own address plans - Chicago roundtable; sends notes (Box 14)
      - 1939 Nov 28; a.l.s. 2 p; social sciences integration (Box 14)
      - 1947 Nov 22; a.l.s. 2 p; meeting plans; Willits and University of Chicago Press plans; social sciences integration (Box 14)
      - 1947 Dec 13; a.l.s. 2 p; Fisher's death; NB - Universities Committee conference, Burns (Box 14)